Guide to the Lewis Madison Terman Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lewis Madison Terman papers
1910-1992
SC0038
Terman, Lewis Madison, 1877-1956
278.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Terman Study Group, Frederick E. Terman, and Shirley Weingarten. Additional materials transferred from Department of Psychology, 2013.
Information about Access
Study participant files & questionnaires restricted due to compliance with Special Collections and University Archives’ Access to Health Information of Individuals Policy: http://library.stanford.edu/spc/using-our-collections/reading-room-policies-procedures/access-health-information. All other materials are open for research.
Biography
Lewis Madison Terman was born in Johnson County, Indiana, on January 15, 1877. He received his A.B. and A. M. from Indiana University and his Ph.D. from Clark University. He came to Stanford in 1910 to teach in the Department of Education; from 1910 to 1916 he worked on constructing an American version of Binet's intelligence test, which he reported in The Measure of Intelligence (Houghton, Mifflin, 1916).
His success with this brought him to the attention of the U. S. Army; he was a member of the committee on Psychological Examination of Recruits and of the Committee on Classification of Personnel, U. S. Army, 1918-1919, and served as a major in the division of psychology, Surgeon General's Office, Washington, D. C.
He returned to Stanford in 1919 as a professor of psychology and taught until 1943, when he was appointed professor emeritus, a position he held until his death in 1956. In 1919 he began his study of gifted children, which he published in The Genetic Studies of Genius, Vol. I, II, and II.
He was a member of the following organizations: The American Association for the Advancement of Science, the American Psychological Association (president, 1923), the National Educational Association, the National Society for the Study of Education, the National Academy of Sciences, Phi Beta Kappa, and Sigma Xi.
Among his other publications were The Stanford Achievement Test, 1923; Children's Reading, 1925; Sex and Personality, 1936; Marital Happiness, 1938; and The Gifted Child Grows Up, 1947.
Scope and Content
Terman's papers include correspondence and data for his study of the gifted; professional correspondence with colleagues; and correspondence and data on tests and testing: Army Alpha and Beta tests, Stanford revision of the Binet-Simon Intelligence scale, Stanford Achievement Test, Terman McNemar Test of Mental Ability, Terman Group Test, Attitude-Interest Analysis Tests, and Male Female Tests.
Access Terms
Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977; Commission on Problem Children.; Cubberley, Ellwood Patterson, 1868-1941; Hilgard, Ernest R. (Ernest Ropiequet), 1904-2001; International Commission on Eugenics..; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Shneidman, Edwin S.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Faculty.;; Stanford University. Department of Psychology.; Terman, Lewis Madison, 1877-1956; Tolman, Ruth.; Wilbur, Ray L., (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949; Yerkes, Robert Mearns, 1876-1956.; Education of children.; Eugenics.; Gifted children.; Intelligence tests.; Stanford-Binet test.
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, Series 1
  - Correspondence concerning the series, "Measurement and Adjustment"
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Allen, Richard D. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Corning, H. M. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Dickson, Virgil E. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Gray (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Otis, Arthur S. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Peterson, Joseph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Washburne, Carleton (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Wells, F. L. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Wood, Ben D. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "A - Z" general (Box 1, Folder 11-32)
  - Almack, J. C. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Association of American Universities, "Nov. 10" (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Book Reviews (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Bureau of Juvenile Research (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bureau of Management Research (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Character and Personality (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Children's Reading (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Commission on Problem Children (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Commonwealth Club (San Francisco) (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Co-operative Test Fund (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Co-operative Test Service (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cubberley, E. P. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "B - C" general (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Deep Springs School (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eugenics Committee (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Eugenics, International Commission on (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Exceptional Children (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Family Relations, Institute of (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - General Education Board (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Goddard, Henry (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Golf (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "E - F - G" general (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Hanna, Maynard B. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Human Betterment Foundation (Gosney, E. S.) (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Hygiene School Child (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "H" general (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Industrial Relations Association (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - International Congress of Genetics (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Jordan, David Starr (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Junior Foundation, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Junior Home Magazine (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Kappa Delta Pi (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - "I - J - K" general (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - May, Dr. Mark A. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Murchison, Carl (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - "M" general (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Society for the Study of Education (N.S.S.E.) 1928 meeting (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "P" general (Box 3, Folder 5a)
  - Rossanoff, A. J. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Shepherd, N. D. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stillman lectures (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Superior Students, Committee on Provisions for (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "T" general (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Vocational Guidance Magazines (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Whipple, Guy M. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - "W - X - Y -Z" general (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Data for Marriage Study, Gifted Subjects, Series 2
  - Psychological Factors in Marital Happiness--Reviews, Comments, Queries (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - E. Lowell Kelly, Marriage Follow-Up Forms (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Donald P., Marriage Study (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Marital Happiness Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Orgasm, Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Scoring Keys: Marital Happiness, Sex Adjustment Aptitude for Marriage (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Current (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Marriage Adjustment Projects (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Data (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Relationships Between Husband and Wife on Husband & Wife and Husband on Wife, Ratings on Traits: also Scatters (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Factor Analysis (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Weights: Bernreuter, Strong, Ideals, Family Background (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - High-Low, Sampling Data (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Index Items, High vs. Low (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - High-Low Comparison (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hand Distributions of Happiness Data: Church Membership, Activities, Interests, etc. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Sex Adjustments, Data and Weights for Scoring (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Orgasm, Hand Tabulations, Correlations, Means, etc. (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Critical Ratios (CR's) to Check (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Trait Rating vs. Birth Position (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Index Items, Means, Tabulations (Some Comparisons: Gifted and Not, Hus.; Gifted and Not, Wife) (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Happiness Distributions and Curves (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Happiness Index, Miscellaneous, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Old Weights vs. New Weights, Correlations (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Marriage Happiness Data, Ready to Use (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Happiness Score (Revision) (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Activities, Critical Ratios: Happy vs. Unhappy Groups (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Reliabilities (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Happiness Index, Weights and Items (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Background Factors, Calculations and Critical Ratios (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - High-Low Critical Ratios: Trait Ratings, Ideals, Activities (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Strong Items, High-Low Critical Ratios (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Corrrelations of Marital Happiness with Sex, Aptitudes (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Non-Classifiable Correlates with Happiness (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Composite Aptitude Scores, Marital Happiness Scores and Sex Scores (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Biserial Correlations of Index Items with Total Happiness Scores (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Index Data Discarded, May 1947 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Husband--Happiness Score; Weights, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Wife--Happiness Scores; (No further use, May 1947), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Background of Marriage (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Orgasm, Data (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Happiness Scores vs. Concept Mastery (CM) (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Mean Happiness Scores, Miscellaneous Marriage & Background (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Intercorrelations (Husband and Wife), Happiness Charts, Aptitudes, etc. (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Predictions, Happiness (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Unfinished Data, Hierarchy and Birth Order (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Family Background: Data, Means, Critical Ratios, etc. (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Traits--by self: Data, Critical Ratios (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Trait Ratings (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Trait Ratings, Husband-Wife Differences (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - One more happy, another less (Data on couple where one member much happier than spouse) (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Bernreuter Calculations, High-Low, Critical Ratios (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Bernreuter Data: Means & High-Low (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Ideals: Means & High-Low (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Strong Data: Means & High-Low (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Ages of Subject, Age Differences with Spouses, Age at Marriage, Miscellaneous Means Happiness Scores, etc. (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Terman Data Study Tape, 1 computer tape(s) (Box 31)
- Manuscripts and Miscellaneous Material, Series 3
  - Japanese Association and Study of Japanese Children, Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Transcript of A.E. Wiggam (Member, Ed. Stff, Amer. Mag.) interview with Terman (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Three Reprints: "I.Q. of Francis Galton," "How Army Uses Individual Differences," and "Courses in Psychology for Students' Army training Corps." (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Vows of Everiti, extra copies (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Examiner's Guides (4 copies) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bernadine Schmidt Controversy (articles and letters) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Morale project, Outlines, Correspondence, etc., 1942: (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Citizens for Victory" (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Sample of Letter Heads, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Lewis M. Terman (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Test of Marital Happiness and Marital Happiness as Related to Background of Marriage (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Background of Marriage (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sex Adjustments and Their Relation to Marital Happiness (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Test of Aptitude for Marriage (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Manuscripts (articles and book chapters), 1945-1949 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Seminar Reports by graduate students of LMT for courses on Biology (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Radio Broadcast Manuscript (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Manuscripts not Published (articles) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Unpublished Papers of Terman (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Articles, Manuscripts (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - LMT's Notes and Clippings for psychology of Genius (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Biography of Genius; also Selected General References on Genius (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Manuscripts, 1 (articles and chapters from books) (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Manuscripts, 2 (articles and chapters from books) (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Helen Marshall Speech AASA, San Francisco, Feb. 27, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - 1962 study of Aging: Corresp., Reprints, mss. (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Reprints and Corresp., "The Relationship between Achievement Motivation and Eminence in Terman Gifted Group," Frederick J. McDonald (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - McDonald Manuscript (see folder 27) (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Terman-Lippman Controversy (Articles in New Rep.) (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Two Photographic Plates of L.M. Terman (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Typescripts (Box 29)
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Materials and Administrative Files (Box 30)
- Books and Reprints, SERIES 4
  - Reprints, 1909-1950s (Box 5)
  - Memoir of National Academy of Sciences, vol. 15, 1921, containing the report of the committee at Vineland, NJ; signed by Terman (Box 6)
  - Reprints (Box 7)
  - Books and reprints (Box 9)
    This box contains a fairly complete collection of Terman's articles, most present as reprints. There are a few books: Measuring Intelligence, Terman and Merrill, 1973; Memoirs of the National Academy of Sciences, vol. 15, 1921, containing the report of the committee at Vineland, N.J., of which Terman was a member; History of Psychology in Autobiography, vol. 2, containing an article by Terman, "Trails to Psychology," (an autobiography), 1932; Condensed Guide for the Stanford Revision of the Binet-Simon Intelligence Tests, 1920 by L. M. Terman; The Psychological Register, vol. 3, 1932, containing a brief biography and an extensive bibliography of Terman; Studies in Personality, 1942, a collection of articles contributed in honor of L. M. Terman; and several other books, not written by or for Dr. Terman, but once owned by him.
- Terman Study of the Gifted: Material Concerning Original Investigation, 1921-1985; Series 5
  - Endowment for Gifted Study, Early Efforts (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Commonwealth Fund, General, 1922-1928 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Commonwealth Fund, First Grant
    - Application (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Reports (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Budget (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - General (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Commonwealth Fund, Second Grant
    - Application (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Reports (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - General (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Anthropometric Measurements (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Medical Examinations (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Application to Commonwealth Fund for a study on influences of heredity and environment on I.Q. scores, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Commonwealth Fund, grant, 1927 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Publications, 1922 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Selection of Assistants, 1921 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Fuller, Florence, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Goodenough, Florence, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Marshall, Helen, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Yates, Mrs. D., Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence
    - Baldwin, B.T. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Bronson, Dr. Edith (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Moore, Dr. Albert H. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Sex Ratio (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Re: Tests (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Suggestions for Making Survey of Gifted Children (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Progress Reports and Summaries (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Preliminary Reports, 1-7 (Box 10, Folder 28-34)
  - Tables used in First Published Report (not complete number) (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Manuscript I, Miscellaneous fragments and chapters of books on study of gifted (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Manuscript II, Miscellaneous fragments and chapters of books on study of gifted (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Standards for admission to Gifted Group (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Order of Filing & Symbols, 1921-22 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Instructions to Fieldworker re: Tests (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - City Survey (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - County Survey (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Tests used for Foreign Children (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - High School Survey (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Weekly Reports, blank copies (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Metabolism Records (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Mss. Of "Home and School Information Blanks" (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Height-Weight-Age Tables (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Barr Taussig Scale, Revision (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Clippings re: Gifted Children Survey (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - Parent Requests, Children not Included in Gifted Group, Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - National Intelligence Test (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Army Group Examination Alpha (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Terman Group Test (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Grade Norms, Terman Group Test (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Stanford Achievement Tests and General Information Tests (later, part of Stan. Achiev. Tests) (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Test Norms (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Tests and Keys: Raubenheimer-Cady, Woodworth, Wyman (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Norms for Character and Personality Tests (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Method for Correcting Binet's I.Q.'s (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Control Means for Wyman Interest Test (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Interest and Personality Test, I-V (Box 10, Folder 62-66)
  - Character and Personality Test, Battery (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Character and Personality Test, raubenheimer & Cady (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Play and Games, Norms, etc. (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Information blanks and report forms used in the Terman study of the gifted, 1921-1985
- Collection of Data on Child Prodigies, Series 6
  - Gifted Strangers, Queries, etc., Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, Notes on Children Whose Names or Locations are Unknown (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cases below standard (standard for project) Tested by Request (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Data and Correspondence on various child prodigies, listed alphabetically by child
    - "A-B" (Box 11, Folder 4-5)
    - Benson, Elizabeth (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Brant, Ruth (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Brown Family (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Brown Family Tests (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Brown, Verne Brainard; Brown, Phyllis Jane; Brown, Molly Cornelia (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - "C-G" (Box 11, Folder 11-15)
    - Geballe, Ronald & Teddy (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Gilbreth (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Greenwood, Arther (special) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "H-K" (Box 11, Folder 19-21)
    - Kice, John Lord (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - King, Janice (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - "L-R" (Box 11, Folder 24-28)
    - Rude, Sarett (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - "S-W" (Box 11, Folder 30-33)
    - "X, Y, Z" (Box 11, Folder 33A)
    - Weisberg, Thomas (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Clippings re: Prodigies, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 35-36)
- Testing: Miscellaneous Data, Correspondence, Examples and Keys, SERIES 7
  - Army Tests, Instructions, Committee on Classification of Personnel in the Army, Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Army Alpha & Pre-Alpha Tests (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Army Alpha Test, Revisions (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Alpha & Beta Tests, Interpretation and Statistics (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Army Beta Tests (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Army Point scale (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Army Performance Scale (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Army Literacy Test (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Army-Original Individual Test (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Army Binet Test (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Trial Scores (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Blanks (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Manual Keys (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - National Research Council re: School Intelligence Tests, 1919-1921 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Stanford Achievement Test Revision; also Preliminary Correspondence, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Stanford Achievement Test Correspondence, 1937-1940 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Stanford Achievement Test, Correspondence Concerning Revision, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Stanford Achievement Test, Norms (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Terman McNemar Test Of Mental Ability, Examples and Keys (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Terman McNemar Test, Correspondence Concerning Revision (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Stanford Group Test, Blanks and Manual (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Terman Group Test, Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Terman Group Test, Translations (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Later Maturity, a Study (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Kieth Sward Test, Later Maturity (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Committee for Study of Sex Variants (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Attitude-Interest Analysis Tests: Examples, Keys, Stencils (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Revised Aptitude-Interest Scales, Rob Ross (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Ross Aptitude-Interest Scale (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Clippings: Sex Differences (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Male-Female Test, Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Stanford Revision pf Binet-Simon Tests: Record Booklets and Guide (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Stanford-Binet Test "Pirated", 1916 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Stanford-Binet Test, Correspondence re (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Stanford-Binet Funds (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Sanford-Binet Tests, Correspondence re: 1937 Revision (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - New Binet Revision, 1955 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Concept Mastery Test, Examples and Answer Forms (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Sagacity Test: Proposals, Outlines, Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Absurd Pictures (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - Joke Tests (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Freak Tests (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Fables--LM (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Hoover Poll on WWII, Oct. 1941 (Box 12, Folder 44)
- Personal and Professional Correspondence, SERIES 8
  - "A" Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - American Association for Gifted Children (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - American Association of Marriage Counselors (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - American Philosophical Society (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - American Psychological Association Symposium on Gifted (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Anderson, Edward. E. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Angell, Frank (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Annual Reviews, Inc. (Psychology) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Atlantic Union (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "B" Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Banta, Arthur (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Barker, Roger (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Bennett, Margaret (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Bingham Lecture (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Bliven, Bruce (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Boisen, Anton T. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Bonbright, Dr. Elizabeth (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Boring, E.G., 1924-1955 (Box 13, Folder 18-20)
  - Boyers, Dr. Luther (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Bradway, Katherine (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - British Psychological Society (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Burks, Barbara (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - "C" Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Canterbury College (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Cattell, Raymond (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Cesselin, Felix (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Child Psychology, Manual of (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Child Research, National Institute of, Act (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Civilian Conservation Corps (C.C.C.) (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Conrad, Herbert S. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Cox, Catherine see also Miles, Catherine Cox (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Cree see Johnson, Winifred (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Cubberley, E.P. (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - "D" Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Duncan, Fred (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Emmons, P.C. (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Engineers Northwest (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Eugenies Society (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - "F" Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Federation of American Scientists (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Fenton, Norman, 1923-1956 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Fishbein, Morris, M.D. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Foreign Friends (Box 14, Folder 6-6A)
  - Fortune, R.F. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Fosberg, I.A. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - "G" Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Gerontological Society, Inc. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Gesell, Arnold L. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Goethe, C.M. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Goodenough, Florence, 1925-1956 (Box 14, Folder 13-14)
  - "H" Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Harlow, Harry (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Hersey, John (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Hilgard, E.R. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Hollingworth, Leta (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Holman, Dr. Emile (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Hutchins, Edward (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - "I - J" miscelaneous (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - International Congress of Psychology (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Jackson, Dr. Frederick E. (Box 14, Folder 24)